In this video, we are going to move beyond our discussion of Run-time Organization
在本视频中，我们将超越对运行时组织的讨论
and begin talking about code generation And in this first you know, it was
开始讨论代码生成，在这第一个中，您知道，它是
probably quite a long series of videos on code generation, we are gonna talk about
可能会有相当长的一系列关于代码生成的视频，我们将讨论
the simplest model for code generation which is called a stack machine. So, in a
最简单的代码生成模型，称为堆栈机。所以，在一个
stack machine, you might guess that the primary storage is some kind of a stack
堆栈机器，您可能会猜想主存储是某种堆栈
and you would be right. In fact, the only storage that the stack machine has is the
那你就是对的。事实上，堆栈机器拥有的唯一存储空间是
stack And the way the stack machine works is that it executed an instruction, and
堆栈和堆栈机器的工作方式是它执行指令，并且
all instruction have the form. There's some function of some arguments and they
所有的说明书都有这样的形式。有些论点有一些作用，它们
produce one result. And what that does is it'll pop in upper hands for the stack so
产生一个结果。它所做的就是它会在堆栈中占据上风，所以
the arguments a1 through an are stored at the top of the stack. It will then compute
参数A1到An存储在堆栈的顶部。然后它将计算
the function f using those operands and it will push the result r back on top of the
函数f使用这些操作数，它将把结果r推回到
stack. Okay, So, let's take a look at a simple example. Let's see how we would
堆栈。好的，那么，我们来看一个简单的例子。让我们看看我们会怎么做
compute seven plus five using a stack machine. So, we would have our stack And
用堆叠机计算7加5。所以，我们会有我们的堆栈
initially the stack might have, already have some stuff on it but we don't care
最初堆栈可能有，已经有一些内容了，但是我们不在乎
what that stuff is and so it will execute seven plus five. What we would do, well
那是什么，所以它会执行7加5。我们会怎么做，好吧
first we will have to get the seven and the five out of the stack so as we get
首先，我们必须将7和5从堆栈中取出，这样我们就可以得到
pushed on stack and we'll see more about how that happens in a minute. And let's
推送到堆栈上，我们将立即看到更多关于这是如何发生的。让我们
say that seven and five were both on the stack. And so now we wanted to compute the
假设七号和五号都在堆栈上。所以现在我们想要计算
addition on seven and five so, addition takes two arguments so we would pop the
7和5的加法因此，加法需要两个参数，所以我们将弹出
two arguments off the stack. And we wined up with the five and the seven Pop-up the
堆栈中的两个参数。我们赢了5个和7个弹出式菜单
stack. We will perform the operation plus and then the result will get push back
堆栈。我们将执行加法运算，然后结果将被推送
under the stack. So this would be good to twelve and then twelve will get push back
在堆栈下面。所以这对12是好的，然后12会被推回去
on to our stack. Okay. And I noticed that I did indicate that there might be some
加入我们的队伍。好吧。我注意到我确实暗示过可能会有一些
other stuff on this stack already. Let me give that stuff a name. And let me talk
这堆东西上已经有其他东西了。让我给那东西起个名字。让我来谈谈
about one very important property of the stack machine. So, those we have evaluated
堆叠机的一个非常重要的特性。所以，我们评估过的那些
seve n+5, we round up in the situation where the results of that operation was on
Sevn+5，我们在操作结果打开的情况下进行四舍五入
top of the stop of the stack. Okay, and the initial stack contents was unchanged.
堆栈停靠点的顶部。好的，初始的堆栈内容没有改变。
This stack, the stack that was below the arguments that we are interested in didn't
这个堆栈，我们感兴趣的参数下面的堆栈没有
get modified. Okay. So, we have survived through all the operations unchanged. And
去修改一下吧。好吧。所以，我们安然无恙地度过了所有的手术。和
this is an important property of the stack machine. That we will exploit and the
这是堆叠机的一个重要特性。我们要利用的是
general to say what the general property is when you evaluate an expression the
一般表示在计算表达式时的一般属性是什么
result of the expression will be on top of the stack and the contents of the stack
表达式的结果将位于堆栈的顶部，并且堆栈的内容
prior to the beginning evaluation of the expression will be preserved. So, now
开始之前表达式的求值将被保留。那么现在
let's take by how we could program a stack machine. So, let's have a language with
让我们来看看如何对堆叠机进行编程。所以，让我们用一种语言
just two instructions in it. We can push an engine run to the stack and then we
里面只有两条说明。我们可以将引擎运行推送到堆栈，然后我们
have the operation add which will add the two integers on the top of the stack. And
使用操作add，该操作将把堆栈顶部的两个整数相加。和
now, let's take a look at this program which pushes seven and then pushes five
现在，让我们看一下这个程序，它先推7，然后推5
and then does an add. So, let's think about how this program would work. Okay,
然后进行加法运算。那么，让我们来考虑一下这个项目是如何运作的。好吧,
so we have our stack contents and now, and the first instruction is to push seven. So
现在我们有了堆栈内容，第一条指令是压入7。所以
wined up with the seven on the stack, added to the stack and now we push five.
与堆栈上的七个人一起喝酒，添加到堆栈中，现在我们推五个。
Okay. And so the next step, we'll have five and seven on top of the stack then
好吧。所以下一步，我们将有5个和7个在堆栈的顶部
we'll perform the add and then we'll pop these two elements off the stack and add
我们将执行相加，然后将这两个元素从堆栈中弹出并相加
them and push the result back on. And we'll wind up with twelve on the stack and
并将结果推回。我们最后会有12个人在堆栈上
again the original stack contents are preserved. Now, what interesting property
再次保留原始堆栈内容。现在，什么有趣的属性
of stack machine code is that the location of the upper hands and result is not
堆栈机器代码的关键是上手的位置和结果不是
exquisitely stated in the instruction. And that's because these instructions always
说明书中写得很精美。那是因为这些指示总是
refer to the top of the stack. And this is in contrast were register machine or
请参阅堆栈的顶部。与此形成对比的是寄存机或
register instructions that explicitly name where they take their upper hands from and
注册明确指定它们的上手位置和位置的指令
where they put the results. So for example you might be familiar from seeing some
他们把结果放在哪里。举个例子，你可能会因为看到一些
machine code or assembly code in the past or and add instruction by typically take
机器代码或汇编代码在过去或与加法指令通常采取
three registers, two for the arguments, two for the registered
三个寄存器，两个用于参数，两个用于已注册的
arguments are gonna be added together and one for the destination for the result
参数将被加在一起，一个参数用于结果的目的地
where in the stack machine we just have. A single word add and no explicit naming of
在堆叠机的什么地方我们只有。只有一个单词add，没有显式命名
the arguments because it's fixed, where the arguments will come from. The
论点，因为它是固定的，论点将从哪里来。这个
arguments will always be popped from the stack and the result will always be placed
参数将始终从堆栈中弹出，并且结果将始终放置
back on top of the stack. And. The interesting property here is that it leads
回到堆栈的顶端。和。这里有趣的属性是它引导
to more compact programs because we have to say less in the instructions the
更紧凑的程序，因为我们必须在指令中少说
programs themselves are actually quite a bit smaller than register machine
程序本身实际上比寄存器机器小得多
programs. And this is one of the reason, reasons that Java bytecode uses a stack
程序。这也是Java字节码使用堆栈的原因之一
evaluation model because it leads to more compact programs and especially in the
评估模型，因为它导致更紧凑的程序，特别是在
early days of Java when it was very expensive to ship these programs around
Java的早期，那时到处运送这些程序非常昂贵
the Internet to download them, having very small compact code was a good property.
在互联网上下载它们，有非常小的压缩代码是一个很好的属性。
And by we might wonder why would we prefer register machine and the answer is that
我们可能会想，为什么我们更喜欢登记机，答案是
register machine code is generally faster because we can place the data exactly
寄存器机器码通常更快，因为我们可以准确地放置数据
where we wanted to be. We will generally have fewer, you know, immediate operations
我们想去的地方。我们通常会有较少的，你知道的，立即行动
and less manipulation of the stack, pushing and popping stuff to get to the
减少了对堆栈的操作，推入和弹出内容即可到达
data that we want. And then it turns out that there isn't inter-media point between
我们想要的数据。然后，事实证明，在媒体之间没有中间点
a pure stack machine and a pure register machine, that's interesting. This is
一台纯粹的堆叠机和一台纯粹的寄存器机器，这很有趣。这是
called an N register stack machine. And conceptually, the idea of the N register
称为N寄存器堆栈机。从概念上讲，N寄存器的概念
stack machine is to keep the. Top end locations of the stack in registers. And
堆叠机是用来保存的。寄存器中堆栈的顶端位置。和
the particular variant of the un-resourced stack machine that we particularly
没有资源的堆叠机的特定变体，我们特别
interested in is the one register stack machine because the terms that you get
感兴趣的是单寄存器堆栈机器，因为
widely benefit by even having a single register that's dedicated to the top of
广泛受益，即使只有一个寄存器专门用于
the stack. This register is called the accumulator so the dedicated registry here
堆栈。此寄存器称为累加器，因此此处的专用注册表
is called the accumulator. It's called that because intuitively it accumulates
被称为累加器。之所以这样叫是因为直觉上它会积累
the results of operations and then all the other data lives on the stack. So, what is
操作的结果，然后所有其他数据都存储在堆栈中。那么，什么是
the advantage of a one register stack machine? Well, let's think about the add
单寄存器堆栈机器的优势是什么？好的，让我们来考虑一下
instruction and how it works in a pure stack machine? So, in the pure stack
指令以及它在纯堆栈机器中是如何工作的？因此，在纯堆栈中
machine, what is the add instruction going to do it's going to pop two arguments from
机器，加法指令要做什么它将从下面弹出两个参数
the stacks, a five and seven. And it's going to add them and then it's gonna put
堆栈，5号和7号。它会把它们相加，然后它会把它们
the result back onto the stack. And let's just name the rest of the stack contents
将结果放回堆栈。让我们将堆栈内容的睡觉命名为
there. And that requires three memory operations. After load, two arguments and
那里。这需要三次内存操作。加载后，两个参数和
then store one result. But in the one razor stack machine, the add operation
然后存储一个结果。但是在一个剃须刀堆叠机中，加法操作
actually does a lot of its work out of the one register. So, the one of the arguments
实际上它的很多工作都是在一个寄存器之外完成的。所以，其中一个论点
is already stored in the register because that's the conceptually the top of the, of
已经存储在寄存器中，因为从概念上讲，这是
the stack. And, the result will be pushed back on the top of the stack which again
堆栈。并且，结果将被推回到堆栈的顶部，该堆栈再次
is just the accumulated register. So here, one of the arguments in the right are both
就是累加的寄存器。所以在这里，右边的一个论点都是
taking from registers and there's only one memory reference to get the second
从寄存器中获取，并且只有一个内存引用来获取第二个
argument from the portion of the stack that's stored in the memory. So in
参数来自存储在内存中的堆栈部分。所以在
general, let's think about how we would evaluate and arbitrary expression using a
一般情况下，让我们考虑一下如何使用
stack machine. So now this isn't I should say, you know, just stack machine called
堆叠机。所以这不是我应该说的，你知道，只是堆叠机，叫做
like we're looking at it before. This is not just a sequence of bytecode level
就像我们之前看到的一样。这不仅仅是字节码级别的序列
operations, this is actually a full expression as you might find in Kuhl so
操作，这实际上是一个完整的表达式，您可能会在Kuhl中找到，因此
there are other complex expressions nested inside of some operation. All right. And
在某些操作中还嵌套了其他复杂表达式。好的。和
so, forget the operation that takes N arguments and those arguments are
所以，忘掉接受N个参数的操作，这些参数是
expression that themselves needs to be evaluated so here's a general strategy for
表达式本身需要求值，所以这里有一个通用策略
doing that with the stack machines. So, for each of the sub-expression, each of
使用堆叠机可以做到这一点。因此，对于每个子表达式，每个
the arguments in order we're going to evaluate it recursively using the same
参数的顺序是，我们将使用相同的
stack machine strategy and that will end up putting the result when we evaluate EI,
堆叠机策略，这将在我们评估EI时最终将结果放入其中，
recursively the results will be in the accumulator. And so the results is in the
递归地，结果将在累加器中。所以结果在
accumulator, alright. And then we're going to push that results onto the memory
累加器，好的。然后我们将把结果推送到内存中
stack. So we'r e going to take that results and we're gonna free up the
堆栈。所以我们要把结果拿出来，我们要把
accumulator and save it on the stack, the portion of stack that's in memory, okay.
累加器，并将其保存在堆栈上，堆栈的一部分在内存中，好的。
So we do this evaluating the sub-expressions for the first and -one
因此，我们计算第一个和-1的子表达式
arguments. So everything except the last one, okay. We're gonna use the same
争论。所以除了最后一个，所有的都是，好的。我们会用同样的
strategy, for the last one, for en. We just evaluate. We don't push the result on
战略，为最后一个，为恩。我们只是评估一下。我们不会把结果推后
the stack. That just means that the result is left in the accumulator okay so now we
堆栈。这只意味着结果留在累加器中，好的，那么现在我们
have one of the arguments of the accumulator. The last one we evaluated and
有一个累加器的参数。上一次我们评估的是
the other in line as one are o the top of the portion of the stack that's in memory.
排成一行的另一个是o，在内存中的堆栈部分的顶部。
So that what we all have to do is we pop in -one values from the stack and combine
因此，我们都要做的是从堆栈中弹出一个值并合并
any compute up using the -one values plus the value of the accumulator and we store
使用-1值加上累加器的值的任何计算，我们存储
the result back into the accumulator, okay. So that's the general strategy for
把结果放回累加器，好的。这就是我们的总体战略
evaluating an expression using a stack machine. So let's do this now for a simple
使用堆栈机器计算表达式。所以现在让我们来做个简单的
example. Let's take our same example that we've been using and let's evaluate the
举个例子。让我们以我们一直使用的相同示例为例，让我们评估
expression seven plus five. So, how we're gonna do that? Well, we're evaluating a
表达式七加五。那么，我们要怎么做呢？嗯，我们正在评估一个
plus expression and that takes two arguments, two expression as the way to
加号表达式，它接受两个参数，两个表达式作为
evaluate each of those. So first we evaluate the expression seven. Let me
评估其中的每一个。所以首先我们计算表达式7。让我
actually, let me draw our stack here. Okay, so we have our initial content to
实际上，让我在这里画个句号。好的，我们的初始内容是
the stack, we have our initial accumulator. And so now we're evaluating
堆栈，我们就有了初始累加器。所以现在我们正在评估
seven, okay? And of course a constant loose evaluate to itself and the result is
七个，好吗？当然，对自身进行持续宽松的评估，结果是
toward the accumulator, okay? So that's the first step after evaluating seven. And
对着蓄电池，好吗？所以这是评估七个之后的第一步。和
now because that's the first argument to plus, it has to get pushed on to the
现在因为这是加号的第一个参数，所以它必须被推到
stack, the portion of the stack in main memory. So. Now, we have a situation that
堆栈，主内存中堆栈的一部分。所以。现在，我们的情况是
looks like this. All right, in the course to seven is still in the accumulator but
看起来是这样的。好的，在到7点的航程中还在累加器里，但是
we're now about to override it, we're not gonna use that value again. Because the
我们现在要覆盖它，我们不会再使用该值。因为
next thing we're gonna do is evaluate the second argument to plus and that happens
接下来我们要做的是将第二个参数求值为+，这会发生
to be in this case also a constant expression five and so that will get
在这种情况下也是一个常量表达式5，所以它将得到
evaluated and then stored in the accumulator. Okay, so I will override the
求值，然后存储在累加器中。好的，所以我会重写
seven. This will be five there, all right? And now, we have evaluated both arguments.
七。这里是五个人，好吗？现在，我们评估了这两个论点。
Okay, remember in the case of just having two arguments. The first argument gets
好的，记住在只有两个论点的情况下。第一个参数得到
evaluated and saved on the stack so it doesn't, so we don't lose the value when
评估并保存在堆栈上，这样它就不会丢失，因此在执行以下操作时不会丢失该值
we evaluate the second argument. And the second argument we uses is the last one we
我们评估第二个论点。我们使用的第二个参数是我们使用的最后一个参数
can just leave in the accumulator And that way actually evaluates the plus. Okay, so
可以直接留在累加器中，这样就可以计算加号。好的，那么
we do the accumulator gets the accumulator plus the top of the memory stack. So in
我们这样做，累加器获得累加器加上内存堆栈的顶部。所以在
this case, that results in adding seven and five. And we line up and of course we
在这种情况下，结果是7和5相加。我们排好队，当然我们
pop the argument from the memory stack, right. So we have just the original
从内存堆栈中弹出参数，对。所以我们只有原件
contents there and now the value twelve in the accumulator. So, as I think you would
内容和现在累加器中的值12。所以，就像我想的那样
see from the example, the invariant that we're gonna maintain with the stack
从示例中可以看出，我们将使用堆栈维护的不变量
machine is that after we evaluate an expression e, the accumulator holds the
机器是在我们对表达式e求值之后，累加器保存
value of e so the result of evaluating e winds up in the accumulator and the stack is
值，因此计算e的结果在累加器中结束，堆栈为
unchanged. And so the stack, the memory portion of the stack is whatever it was
没变。所以堆栈，堆栈的内存部分是什么
before we start of evaluating e. And this is a very, very important property,
在我们开始评估e之前，这是一个非常非常重要的性质，
expression evaluation preserves the stack. So, now let's look at a more elaborated
表达式求值保留堆栈。那么现在我们来看一个更详细的
example, just slightly more elaborate, three+7+5. And the interesting thing about
例如，只是稍微详细一点，3+7+5，有趣的是
this example. Is that now one of the arguments to the other plus is itself a
这个例子。现在另一个加号的其中一个论点本身就是一个
compound expression. So it would have to be, that would have to be evaluated
复合表达式。所以它必须是，那必须要评估
recursively as part of evaluating the entire expression so let's see how this
递归作为计算整个表达式的一部分，让我们看看这是如何实现的
works. So the first thing that's going to happen or evaluating the outer plus, we're
很管用。所以要做的第一件事就是评估外加，我们是
gonna evaluate the first argument to that plus that's just the constant three so
我要计算第一个参数，加上，这只是常数3，所以
we're gonna load it into the accumulator. And that's the result of evaluating three.
我们要把它装进蓄电池。这就是三次评估的结果。
And now because it's the first argument to the plus, we have to save it before we can
现在因为这是加号的第一个参数，所以我们必须先保存它，然后才能
get around to evaluating the addition itself. So that result is pushed on to the
抽出时间来评估添加本身。因此，结果会被推送到
stack. And now we're g onna evaluate the second argument to the outer plus and that
堆栈。现在我们要将第二个参数求值为外部加号，也就是
itself has two arguments. And the first argument to that, to the inner plus is
它本身有两个论点。关于这一点的第一个论据是，对内部加号的第一个论点是
seven. And so that winds up getting stored in the accumulator, that's the result of
七。所以最终被存储在累加器中，这就是
evaluating seven. And then because the inner plus has two arguments, we have to
评估7号。因为内加号有两个论点，所以我们必须
evaluate the second, evaluate the second argument to the inner plus, the seven has
对第二个求值，对第二个自变量求值为内部加号，7有
to get saved to the stack. So now, the stack has seven three and whenever it had
才能保存到堆栈中。所以现在，堆栈有7，3，只要它有
before we start it. Next, we're gonna evaluate the second argument to the inner
在我们开始之前。接下来，我们将从内部评估第二个论点
plus And so evaluating a constant five will result in five being loaded in the
加法求值为常数5将导致将5加载到
accumulator and now, we have evaluated all the arguments to the inner plus, okay. And
累加器，现在，我们已经将所有参数求值为内部加号，好的。和
so we know from our stack discipline that the last arguments is in the accumulator
因此，我们从堆栈规则中知道最后一个参数在累加器中
and the first argument will be on top of the stack. So the next thing that will
第一个参数将位于堆栈的顶部。所以接下来要做的就是
happen is that we'll pop that second argument from the stack added to the
我们将从堆栈中弹出第二个参数，并将其添加到
accumulator and store back into the accumulator and so now we have the results
累加器，并存储回累加器，现在我们就有了结果。
of the inner plus in the accumulator. We also have the pop, the seven from the
累加器中的内加。我们还有流行音乐，七个来自
stack, okay and finally now we've evaluated the second argument to the outer
堆栈，好的，最后我们对外部的第二个参数求值
plus. So now we can perform the outer edition. And what is that involve that
另外。现在我们可以表演外版了。这又牵涉到什么呢？
takes the stack contents then adds it to the value that is currently on the top of
获取堆栈内容，然后将其添加到当前位于
the stack which is the value three which is what we saved a long time ago now to,
堆栈是我们很久以前保存的值3，
to remember it from what it was to do the other addition and we wind up. After we
从做另一个加法的过程中记住它，最后我们就得到了。在我们之后
pop the stack with fifteen in the accumulator, that's the results of the
在累加器中弹出15的堆栈，这是
entire expression, and notice it's the same stack that we started with. Okay? So
整个表达式，注意这与我们开始时使用的堆栈相同。好吧?所以
evaluating this entire expression, resulted in the, result in any accumulator
对此整个表达式求值，会导致产生任何累加器
and the stack being unchanged And if you looked at that the sub-expression, you can
堆栈保持不变，如果您查看该子表达式，您可以
see that the same things happened. So let's take a look at the evaluation of
确保同样的事情发生。那么我们来看一下这个评价，
seven plus five. So where that take place that started here. Okay. Started at this
七加五。从这里开始，这一切就发生在哪里。好吧。从这个开始
instruction. And, it lasted down to here and you can see that the evaluation of
指示。而且，它一直持续到这里，你可以看到，对
seven + five which encompasses these five expressions resulted in twelve being put
包含这五个表达式的7+5导致了12个
on top of the stack, that's the result of seven + five and it didn't affect the
在堆栈的顶部，这是7+5的结果，它不会影响
contents I'm sorry. It resulted in twelve being placed in the accumulator and it
内容我很抱歉。这导致12个被放置在累加器中，并且它
will left the stack unchanged to where it was when the evaluation of seven plus five
将使堆栈保持不变，直到评估为7加5时的位置
began. So here is where it began and the value we had saved three was on the top of
开始了。这就是它开始的地方，我们节省了3英镑的价值在
the stack and when we're done evaluating seven plus five indeed again the value
堆栈，当我们计算完7加5时，实际上也是值
three and. All the other stuff that was there before are still on the stack.
三加三。以前在那里的所有其他东西都还在堆栈上。